# ABONGILE WILLIAM

Plattekloof 2 · 072 115 1831 abongilewilliam@gmail.com · https://abongile-william.web.app/

I am a 21-year-old ICT Multimedia student currently doing my 3rd year at the Cape Peninsula University of Technology. My current objective is to improve my skills and develop my passion as a Front-End Developer by consistently learning and building projects. My drive and dedication for coding has helped me get this far and I look forward to seeing how I can contribute to the fast-paced industry!

## **EDUCATION**

#### **JANUARY 2018**

## MATRIC, EDGEMEAD HIGH SCHOOL

Distinction in Computer Applications Technology (Computer Literate)
Multiple sport trophies and awards in soccer (Team Player)
Successfully obtained Matric Certificate

#### **JANUARY 2019**

## HIGHER CERTIFICATE IN SOUND PRODUCTION, SAE INSTITUTE

Successfully obtained a Higher Certificate in Sound Production Involved a lot of group work and obtained leadership skills

#### **JANUARY 2019 - CURRENT**

#### ICT IN MULTIMEDIA APPLICATIONS, CAPE PENINSULA UNIVERSITY OF

## **TECHNOLOGY**

2<sup>nd</sup> year average is 72% Great time management skills Good at working in a team

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **NOVEMBER 2016 – DECEMBER 2016**

## **WOOLWORTHS FLEXIBLE EMPLOYEE, WOOLWORTHS**

Working in teams to ensure products are placed and displayed in a neat manner.

Keeps products separated, organized and in good rotation.

Monitors product quality frequently, reporting problems to mitigate safety issues.

Providing excellent customer service, answering questions, and handling complaints from clients.

#### **JANUARY 2019 - FEBUARY 2019**

## **DELIVERY DRIVER, IBUYAMBO**

Loading, transporting, and delivering items to clients or businesses in a safe, timely manner. Reviewing orders before and after delivery to ensure that orders are complete, the charges are correct, and the customer is satisfied.

## **SKILLS**

- HTML
- CSS/SCSS
- Javascript
- UI/UX design
- SEO
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe illustrator

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Perseverance and motivation
- Ability to work under pressure
- Confidence
- Ability to find solutions on Google

# **ACTIVITIES**

While doing my 3<sup>rd</sup> year at varsity I also do personal projects to continue improving my skills so that I can contribute to this fast-paced industry!

## **COVER LETTER**

# DEAR TO WHOM THIS MAY CONCERN,

Are you looking for a Front-End Developer who:

- Is tech savvy
- Has design skills and knowledge of Adobe suite products
- Is driven and self-motivated
- Has experience with front-end technologies such as HTML, CSS/SCSS, JavaScript, Git, etc.
- Is always seeking to learn and grow

If so, then I would be the perfect fit to your company! I am a dedicated and smart worker who solves any challenges presented to him, therefore I believe that I can contribute to the software development industry with the set of skills that I have.

You can contact me via phone(072 115 1831) or email (<a href="mailto:abongilewilliam@gmail.com">abongilewilliam@gmail.com</a>) to schedule an interview. I look forward to hearing from you!

Abongile